欢迎加入OCR小组 qq群906722936 字幕优先发布于群内
趴地上
Stay on the ground now!
别慌
Stay calm,
没人会受伤
anc nobody will be hurt.
不许动
Don't movel
船这么大 他们不可能把所有地方都涵盖到
It's a big boat. They can't cover all of it.
我只看到六个人
- I only count six. -
七个
Seven.
头低下
Head down!
你是船长
You are captain?
对
I am.
是个女人哎
Lady captain.
时代进步了
Progressive.
我喜欢
I like it.
抱歉打搅各位游轮之旅 船长
Apologies for interrupting pleasure cruise, Captain,
但我们本来是打算
but it was our intention
在下一站完成交易的
to conclude our business at the next stop.
可你们却把船掉头了
But you turned boat around.
我们要回去美国水域
We're headed back to U. S. waters.
南边有场热带风暴正在形成
There's a tropical storm building to the south of us.
不会耽误你太久
Eh, we won't keep you long.
我们只是来拿样东西
We're just here to get one thing.
上船 下船 简单
In, out. Simple.
-轻点  -坐下
Sit down.
麻烦站起来
Please stand.
我吗
Me?
不是 为什么是我
- No, why me?
我什么都没做啊 我
I didn't do anything. No, I- -
我没
I didn't- -
I- I didn't- - I didn't do- -
我什么都没做啊
I didn't do anything.
我们现在把这事了结
We end this now.
你把加密狗给我
You give me dongle,
我把老婆还你 塔莎
I give you wife. Tasha!
萝拉
Lola.
作为奖励 捂嘴布就留给你们了
As bonus, we let you keep gag.
老子数到三
I'm going to give you to the count of three.
把加密狗交出来
to hand over the dongle.
- 一  -等
One... Wait a- -
等一下 就等一下
Wait a minutel Just wait a minute.
等等 你搞错了
Wait a minute. You are mistaken.
我们不是你要找的人
We are not who you think we are.
天 我天
Oh, God. Oh, God. -
天呐
Oh, God.
拿去
Take it.
把我所有钱都拿去
Take- take all the money I have.
三
Three. -
他没什么该死的加密狗
He doesn't have any damn donglel
她说得对
She is right.
我们认识这个男的 他说的是实话
We know this man, and he is telling the truth.
-你们知道他说的是真的  -知道
You know this as fact? - We do.
也许我们真找错人了
Maybe we got the wrong couple.
你俩上船多久了
How long have you two been on boat?
我开玩笑的
I'm kidding.
我觉得就是他们
I think it's them.
我刚数到几了
Now where was I?
哦对 三
Oh, yes. Three.
我们都跟你说了他没有
We told you he doesn't have itl
你要去哪儿啊
Where do you think you're going?
我是急救人员
I am a first responder.
你得让我帮这个人
You have to let me help this man.
是吗
Do I?
也许吧
Maybe.
告诉我你把加密狗藏哪了
Tell me where you've hidden the dongle,
也许我会让这人救你
and maybe I'll let this man try to save your life.
我不知道
I don't know.
他没法告诉你
He can't tell you
因为他不知道
...because he doesn't know! -
朱利安
Julian!
干嘛
What?
你任游轮总监期间 彼得森夫妻进行过
How many trips have the Petersons taken with you
多少次旅行
as cruise director?
你跟萝拉什么时候有的婚外情
When did your affair with Lola start?
等等 婚外情
Wait, an affair?
什么
What- what...?
跟萝拉 你说什么呢
Affair with Lola? What are you talking about?
-天  -把他带过来
Oh, GodBring him.
不不不
No, no, no.
不 朱利安和萝拉
No. Julian with Lola.
天呐
Oh, God. Oh, God.
天
Oh, God.
你只勾引过她这一个乘客
Is she the only passenger that you've seduced
好帮你完成你的小小副业吗
into helping you with your Iittle side hustle?
副业 我是说
Side hustle? I- I mean,
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
这步棋很高明
Oh, it's a smart setup.
只要对一个无聊的寻求
Just target a boredl housewife
一点小小冒险的家庭主妇出手
looking for a little adventure,
你甚至都不用踏上陆地
and you don't even have to set foot on dry land
也不用弄脏自己的手
or get your hands dirty.
天
Oh, God.
加密狗
Where.
在
IS...
哪里
...dongle?
先生 我可以向你保证
Sir, I can assure you
我们公司有非常严格的政策
that our company has a very strict policy
禁止与
about fraternizing with- -
我平板电脑里 在我平板里
My iPad. It's in my iPad.
密码是hot4
The password is"hot, "the number 4,
全小写
and all owercase...
lola
天 让我死吧 让我死了吧
Oh, God, let me die. Let me die.
让我死吧
Just let me die. Let me die.
生意完成
Business is concluded.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
享受余下的旅程吧
enjoy the rest of your cruise.
船长女士
Lady Captain
船还给你了
...the ship is yours.
天 求求你
Oh, God, please.
我在陪着你呢
I'm right here with you.
游戏结束 各位
Game over, folks!
嘿 我就要赢了
Hey! I was winning!
-去别处赢去  -全体乘客请注意
Go win somewhere else. - Attention all passengers.
请返回您的客舱房间
Please return to your staterooms
等待进一步指示
and wait for further instructions.
扶他上去 扶他上去 对 慢慢来
Get him up, get him up. Yeah, nice and easy.
全体乘客请注意
Attention all passengers.
请返回您的客舱房间
Please return to your staterooms...
小心 小心点
Be careful, be careful.
等待进一步指示
...and wait for further instructions.
没事的 没事的
－ It's okay, it's okay.
没事 看起来像是贯穿伤
It's all right, it looks like it's a through and through,
-是好事  -感觉并不好
- so that's good. - It doesn't feel good.
我知道 好了
I know, I know. Okay.
-诺曼 对不起  -别说了 走开
－ Oh, Norman, I'm so sorry. - No, go away.
别 走吧
No, come on.
-等我们上岸再求他也来得及  -拜托
You can grovel once we reach dry land. - Please.
坚持住 坚持住 诺曼
- Hang in there, hang in there, Norman.
你怎么知道的
How did you know?
猜的
I guessed.
我一直回想我们第一次见面那晚
And then I kept thinking back to our first night,
你丈夫把你男朋友叫到我们桌边的时候
when your husband brought your boyfriend over to our table,
你故意没看他
how you wouldn't look at him.
就像要瞒着什么事一样
Like you had something to hide.
继续走 坐那边去 坐你犯罪搭档旁边
Go on, sit there, next to your partner in crime.
我去甲板上一趟 医生来了
I'm needed on the bridge. The doctor's here.
去吧 这里交给我们
Go. We got it.
医生
Doctor?
跟我来
Follow me.
看好这俩人
Watch these two.
别担心 我没事
Don't worry, I'm fine.
去死吧
Go to hell.
病人在这里 医生
Here's your patient, Doctor.
天 他是
Oh, dear. Is he- -
他疼晕过去了
He's passed out from the pain.
他怎么会在轮盘赌桌上
What's he doing on a roulette table?
因为离得医务室在船的另一头
Cause your infirmary's on the other side of the ship,
我觉得把他抬那么远不安全
and I didn't think it was safe to carry him that far.
好了 医生 过来 伤口在这边
AlI right, Doc, come here. This is what we're looking at.
腹部中等口径枪伤
It's a medium- caliber gunshot wound to the abdomen.
子弹直接穿透 没留下残余
Bullet made a clean exit,
但可能划伤了他的肝脏
but it could've nicked his liver.
医生
- Doctor?
你是要吐吗
Are you going to be sick?
也许 我是全科医生
Maybe. I'm a GP.
-不是创伤外科医生  -好 你医疗包里有什么
- I'm- I'm not a trauma surgeon. - All right, what's in your medical bag?
有没有止血绷带
Do you have any hemostatic bandages
或者凝血药物
or coagulating granules?
我有晕船药
I have some seasick pills.
也许你该吃一片
Maybe you should take one.
然后去看看拐角那个
And go see that guy around the corner
-鼻子断了的人  -好的好的 这我能行
－ with the broken nose. - Yeah, yeah, yeah. I can, I can do that.
with the broken nose. - Yeah, yeah, yeah. I can, I can do that.
好 你需要什么
AlI right, what do you need?
我的团队
My team.
跑车从侧面撞向Suv
Sports car T- boned the SUV,
导致后者翻滚到轿车上
causing it to roll onto the sedan.
车里两人被困 母亲和一个女儿
We've got two trapped inside- mother and a daughter.
母亲没反应
Mom is not responsive.
救命 我妈妈 她受伤了
Help! My mom, she's hurt!
好 我们会把你俩都救出来的
AlI right, we're gonna get you both out of there.
-你叫什么  -莱克西
- What's your name? - Lexi.
我妈在教我开车
My mom was just giving me a driving lesson.
那人闯红灯 不知道从哪里冒出来的
That guy ran the light, he came out of nowhere.
好的 莱克西 我这位朋友要
AlI right, Lexi, my friend here is gonna have
-给你快速检查一下 好吗  -好的
a quick look at you, okay? - Okay.
莱克西 可以看这里吗 谢谢
Lexi, can you look here, please?
好的
Okay.
脉搏很微弱 但是有
Pulse is thready, but it's there.
瞳孔等大有反应
Pupils equal and reactive.
莱克西 能动动脚趾吗
Lexi, can you wiggle your toes for me?
好 我没事 求求你救救我妈妈
Yes, I'm fine. Just please help my mom.
好 我要这辆车被固定 稳定住
AlI right. I want this car secured and stabilized
-以便把人撤离  -收到 队长
- for extraction. - Copy you, Cap.
那边那位是我们的赛车手吗
Is that our Mario Andretti over there?
对
Yeah.
清醒吗
Field sobriety?
拒绝检查 他“知道自己的权利“
Refuses. He"knows his rights. "
他肯定知道
Mm, I bet he does.
奇米 去看看他
Chim, check him out.
我们得确认在他被送进监狱前
Let's make sure we don't have to take him to the hospital
不用带他去医院
before he gets taken to jail.
收到
Copy that.
找主管来
Look, I want a supervisor.
你重要吗 是管事的吗
Are you important? Do you matter?
先生 这位护理人员需要给你检查一下
Sir, this paramedic needs to take a look at you.
-我没事 离我远点  -先生
- I'm fine. Get away from me. - Okay, sir,
你有可能受伤了
it's possible you've been injured
你甚至都不知道 有时候肾上腺素会
and you don't even know it. Sometimes the adrenaline- -
-我刚说什么来着  -好了 听着
- What did I just say? - A- AII right, listen.
要不我们去路边坐一下
Why don't we just take a seat on the curb
我给你快速检查一下
and I can take a quick look at you?
为什么 这样你就能收我钱了呗 听着
Why? So you can bill me? I, look- -
-先生    -滚开
- Sir- - - Get out of my face!
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey. Okay.
-刚才那是袭击  -我没袭击他
So that is assault. - It's not assault.
-是他把手放我身上了  -行了
He was putting his hands on me. - Come on, man.
我们只是想帮你
We're just trying to help you.
你要再找我麻烦 你的警徽就没了
You come at me again, I'll have your badge.
我都不是警察
I'm not a police officer.
那你以后也别想有机会做了
A- And you won't be anymore either.
-先生 你是拒绝医护吗  -对 我不同意
Sir, are you refusing care? - Yes. I do not consent.
行 威廉警官
Fine. Officer Williams?
-先生  -嘿 不 你不能这么做
Sir. - Hey. No. You can't do that!
你不是被捕
You are not under arrest.
你只是在我们调查期间被拘留了
You're just being detained while we conduct our investigation.
-放开我  -亨
－ Get your hand off me. - Hen,
我知道他挺混蛋的
I know he's being a dick,
但我们真的需要给他进行评估
but we really should evaluate him.
-也许现在他被铐上时正合适  -不 不用管他
Maybe now that he's in cuffs. - No. He's done.
为什么这些醉汉总是搞出这种事故
Why is it that drunks always come out of these things
还能安然无恙
without a scratch?
我这边好了 卸下窗户就行
Good on my side. Let's get the window.
好了 给妈妈戴上护颈圈
AlI right, let's get a C- collar
然后把她拉出来
on the mom and get her out.
宝儿
Baby?
-莱克西  -我在这呢 妈
- Lexi! - I'm right here, Mom.
-你没事吧  -我没事 妈
- You okay? - Yes, I'm fine, Mom.
-他们正在救我们出去   -发 发生什么了
－ They're getting us out. - Wh- What happened?
-他们正在救我们出去  -发 发生什么了
· They're getting us out. - Wh- What happened?
-你们出车祸了  -不
- You were in an accident. - Oh. Oh, no.
有有有人受伤吗
Is, is, is, is anyone hurt?
大家都活下来了
Everyone survived.
谢天谢地
Praise Jesus.
我忍不住想 另一个人
Couldn't help but notice that wasn't a question
可没问过这个问题
the other guy asked.
你是说造成这一切的家伙吗
Oh, you mean the guy who caused this?
你觉得我还能拿到驾照吗
Think I'll still be able to get my license?
不知道
I don't know.
你首先得通过考试对吧
You have to pass the test first, right?
威尔逊队长
Captain Wilson!
我需要赶紧过来 他没有呼吸了
I need you over here! He's not breathing.
解开手铐 我需要他仰面躺着
Uncuff him. I need to get him on his back.
没有脉搏
No pulse.
开始按压
Starting compressions.
-怎么回事  -他一直站着说话来着
- What happened? - H- He was up and talking,
然后说的话突然就变的模糊不清
then his words became gibberish.
突然就倒下了
He just collapsed.
奇米 换我
Chim, switch.
呼叫另一辆救护车
Radio for another ambulance.
打电话给最近的一级创伤中心
And call the closest level- one trauma center.
让神经外科医生待命
Have a neurosurgeon standing by.
收到
Copy that.
这医院的仪器声怪怪的
Those are some peculiar- sounding hospital machines.
那是因为我们在赌场
That's because we're in a casino.
我不会去碰运气
I don't think I'll try my luck.
一直都不太好
Hasn't been very good.
-只会越来越好对吧  -什么意思 总好过
Can only get better, right? - What do you mean, better than
发现你结婚36年的妻子
finding out your wife of 36 years
你独生子的母亲是个国际走私犯
and mother of your only child is an international smuggler
-和荡妇吗  -是 肯定比这个要好
- and a strumpet? - Yeah. Better than that.
鲍比
Bobby.
我们把房子卖了
We sold our house.
搞了个庭院旧货出售 规模很大
We had a yard sale. Big one.
36年累积下来的东西
36 years of accumulated stuff.
那些记忆 我们在所有东西上
Memories. We wrote little
都手写了价签
handwritten prices on everything.
只卖了2800块
We only made$2, 800.
36年啊
36 years.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你和雅典娜结婚多久了
How long have you and Athena been married?
我们刚庆祝了结婚四周年纪念
We just celebrated our fourth wedding anniversary.
那是二婚吧
I guess, second marriage?
是 我们俩都是
Yeah. Second for both of us.
你幸福吗
Are you happy?
嗯
Yeah.
我很幸福
Yeah, I am.
请让我跟诺曼一起吧
Please let me sit with Norman.
他是我老公 他需要我
He's my husband. He needs me.
你真的觉得你老公
Do you really think yours is the face
现在想看见你吗
he wants to be looking at right now?
至少别让我跟他待在一起
At least don't make me stay here with him.
你自找的 萝拉
You made your bed, Lola.
再说了 我需要你们俩待在我能看见的地方
Besides, I need you both where I can see you.
他怎么样了
How is he?
-还能撑住  -别动
Hanging in there. - Hold still.
感觉好点了吗
Feel better?
他的实际情况呢
How is he, really?
他现在稳定下来了 但需要手术
Well, he's stable for now, but he needs a surgeon.
我们需要让他尽快下船
We need to get him off this ship.
你建议我们怎么做
How do you propose we do that?
我会跟船长谈谈
I'll talk to the captain,
看看能不能联系上海岸警卫队
see if we can contact the Coast Guard
用直升飞机接走他
and get him airlifted out of here.
先生 船长让所有客人
Sir, the captain asked all guests
都回到自己房间去
to return to their staterooms.
是 我听见了
Yeah, I heard that,
但你没听见我说的话
but you're not hearing me.
我不会离开这间赌场的
I'm not leaving this casino
除非有人把筹码给我换成现金
until someone cashes me out.
你可以向游轮公司提出这个问题
You can take that up with the cruise line.
我就找船长说
I'll take it up with the captain.
我现在就要和她对话
I want to speak to her now.
不可能
That's not possible.
现在不能打扰她
I can't bother her right now.
打扰一下
Excuse me?
我的队长要和你们船长对话
My captain needs to speak with your captain.
我这就带您去舰桥
I'll escort you to the bridge.
-谢谢  -不是吧 你怎么就行
- Thanks. - Seriously? How did you do that?
因为我说打扰一下了
I said"excuse me. "
这个狡猾的王八蛋
Slippery son of a bitch.
他在医院被宣布死亡
He was pronounced at the hospital.
我知道
I know.
怎么回事
What's going on?
洛杉矶消防局专业服务部
LAFD Professional Services Division.
他们在做笔录
They're taking statements.
内务部的吗 为什么
Internal Affairs? What for?
辛普森局长让你去办公室见他
Chief Simpson wants to see you in Cap's office.
威尔逊队长
Captain Wilson.
辛普森局长
Chief Simpson.
为什么我有种感觉 这个醉酒司机
Why do I have the feeling that this drunk driver
不止是个普通司机这么简单
wasn't just a drunk driver?
首先
First of all,
我们还不知道他是否醉酒
we don't know that he was drunk.
毒检报告还要一段时间才能出来
It'll be a while before the tox results are in.
他的家人坚持说这不可能
His family's insisting there's no way.
好吧
Mm, okay.
那么 他的家人是谁
So, who is his family?
他叫凯尔·奥尔蒂斯
His name was Kyle Ortiz.
他母亲是奥利维亚·奥尔蒂斯
His mother's Olivia Ortiz.
奥尔蒂斯议员
Councilwoman Ortiz.
懂了
Got it.
无意冒犯 长官
With all due respect, sir,
议员并不在这
the councilwoman wasn't there.
她儿子当时已经表现出损伤的迹象
And her son was displaying all the signs of impairment.
所有这些都可能是
All of which could have been indications
致他死亡的脑出血迹象
of the brain bleed that killed him.
但我们不知道 因为我听说
But we don't know that because I'm being told
现在没有人给他做生命体征检查
his vitals weren't even taken at the scene.
他拒绝了我们
He refused care.
我是跟足了程序去做的
I followed protocol.
我只能让你暂时停职
I'm taking you off active duty,
至少要等我们的毒检报告出来再说
at least until we get the tox reports back.
我懂了
I see.
回家去吧 消防员
Go homejfirefighter.
我理解你的要求
I understand what you're asking,
但是抱歉 我做不到
but I'm sorry, I can't do it.
船长 我知道外面有暴风雨
Captain, I realize there's a storm out there,
但是海岸警卫队可以找到我们
but the Coast Guard can navigate that.
不是这个问题 我不能打给海岸警卫队或者任何人
It's not that. I can't call the Coast Guard or anyone else.
-通讯系统坏了  -因为暴风雨吗
Comm systems are down. - From the storm?
蓄意破坏 海盗砸碎的
Sabotage. Pirates smashed everything.
他们甚至把应答器也抢走了
They even took out the transponder,
我们无法向外部传达我们的位置
so we can't even relay our position.
看来他们是想抢先一步
Guess they wanted a head start.
工程部方面有什么进展
What's the update from engineering?
还在进行修补
Still working on that repatch.
好 我这就去下层甲板
Okay. I'm headed below deck.
恐怕彼得森暂时还是你的病人 纳什队长
I'm afraid Mr. Peterson's still your patient, Captain Nash.
如果他情况有变请通知我
Let us know if his condition changes.
-收到  -肯尼 舰桥归你负责了
Copy that. - Kenny, the bridge is yours.
计划下一次旅行吗
- Ah- Planning another trip?
-我的天  -是 他们都用斧子给砍了
Good Lord. - Yeah, they took an axe to it all.
-你修理过了  -算是吧
－ But you repaired it? - Nearly.
也许吧
I think. Maybe.
如果在手动重启期间
If it all doesn't come crashing down
系统没有崩溃 你应该就可以呼叫
during the manual reboot, you should be able
-任何人了  -那就启动吧
to call anyone you want. - Let's fire it up, then.
-他怎么样  -时而昏迷时而清醒
- How is he? - In and out.
他的生命指征很微弱但也很稳定
Uh, his vitals are weak but steady.
你跟船长说过话了
You speak to the captain?
是
Yes, I did.
那这隔离什么时候能结束啊
So, when's this quarantine gonna be over?
有人得把筹码给我换了
Somebody needs to cash me out.
你意识到这里有个人被枪击了吗
Do you realize a man has been shot here?
又不是我开的枪
I didn't shoot him.
你为什么不去自己房间待着呢
Why don't you go to your stateroom?
我想等下会有通知的
I'm sure there'll be an announcement.
这边走
This way.
我妻子呢
Where's my wife?
她去抓坏人了
She went after the snake.
所以你是怎么想的
- So, what was the plan?
躲在船上某处然后
Just hide out somewhere on the ship and then
等我们靠岸时就跑掉
slip away once when we dock?
我打算留下一些私人物品
I was gonna leave some personal items behind as well,
-在栏杆附近  -是啊
near a railing. - Right.
在海上失踪了 因为内疚自杀
Lost at sea, did yourself in out of guilt.
你怎么还随身带着扎带
Why do you have zip ties?
因为他们不让我带手铐上船
Because they wouldn't let me bring my cuffs on the boat.
走
Walk.
我们应该可以了
I think we're gonna be okay.
这是什么鬼
What the hell is this?
撑住 撑住
Hold on, hold on!
-这不公平 亨  -是啊
- It's a bum deal, Hen. - Yeah, it really is.
是 局长也没说是正式停职
Yeah, the chief isn't calling it an official suspension.
只是暂停
Just a"pause. "
我们保证会给科利尔局长
Well, we promise to make Captain Collier's life
找不痛快的
a living hell. -
-谢了  -如果毒检报告
Appreciate that. - What if the tox screen
为阴性呢
comes back negative?
如果他没喝酒呢
You know, what if he wasn't under the influence?
事实上我也不知道
The truth is, I don't know.
奥尔蒂斯议员要找人背锅
Councilwoman Ortiz is looking for someone to blame.
他们 他们不能因为一个错误的决定就解雇你
Well, they- they can't fire you for one bad call.
谁说是错误决定的
Who said it was a bad call?
-他们说的吗  -没 没有
－ Did they? - Um, n- no, no.
-你说的吗  -我 不是
Did you? - M- Me? No.
我 我什么都没说
I- I didn't say anything. Um...
我什么都没看到
I- I didn't really see anything.
就是 我们只是在把一辆车上的人抬走 然后
You know, we- we were cribbing the other car and.
直到他开始快不行了
We didn't even get a good look
我们才来得及看他
at the guy until he was coding.
我们都以为他喝醉了
W- We all thought he was drunk.
他确实喝醉了
H- He was.
我们都能闻到
I mean, we could all smell it.
你闻到了的 对吧
You could smell it, right?
奇米
Chim?
对不起 我什么都没闻到
I'm sorry, I didn't smell anything.
这怎么可能
How is that possible?
你不是离他比我近吗
Y- You were closer to him than I was.
你怎么会闻不到
How could you not smell that?
我不知道 难道我该撒谎吗
I don't know. Was I supposed to lie?
你觉得我希望你撒谎吗
Is that what you think I'd want?
不 我当然不认为你会希望我撒谎
No, of course I don't think you'd want me to lie.
我根本不想和那些人说话
I didn't even want to talk to those guys.
对啊 根本没人想和他们说话
Uh, right. N- Nobody did.
我们只是去回答他们的问题
We just answered their questions.
没人说是你的错
And nobody blamed you.
-嗯  -你忙着担心另一辆车里的受害者
Uh- huh. - You were understandably concerned
大家都理解
for the victims in the other car.
-是他弄出来的受害者  -没错
His victims Exactly.
His victims. Exactly.
如果角色互换 我们中的任何一个人
If the roles were reversed, any one of us
都可能做出同样的决定
might have made the same call.
如果角色互换
And if the roles were reversed,
我会想办法保护你们
I'd find a way to have your backs,
而且我不需要说谎
and I wouldn't have to lie to do it.
回头见
I'll see you around.
也许吧
Maybe.
其他人还好吗
Everyone else okay?
我们撞上冰山了还是怎么的
Yo, we hit an iceberg or something?
是爆炸
That was an explosion.
是工程部那边
That came from engineering.
我们得另找出路
We need to find another way out.
如果我带你出去 上岸停靠时你会放我走吗
If I show you, will you let me go when we dock?
-不可能  -那你就自己
- Not a chance. - Then you'll just have to figure it out
-想办法吧  -不 我不会的
- for yourself. - No, I won't.
因为你不可能坐在这里 让自己被淹死
No way you're gonna sit here and let your ass drown.
船沉鼠要逃 我跟着你就好了
Rats desert sinking ships, so I'm gonna follow you.
你还是接着走吧
You might as well start walking.
你还好吗 诺曼
How you doing, Norman?
实际上我有点晕船
I feel a little seasick, actually.
哦 这我倒是能解决
Oh. I can help with that.
所有乘客请注意
Attention all passengers.
这是一则全体集合通知
This is a general muster call.
请到预先指定的集合地点报到
Report to your predesignated muster stations.
我们要弃船了吗
Are we abandoning ship?
不一定
Not necessarily.
全体集合只是以防万一
General muster is just a precaution.
拿不到我赢的钱我是不会上救生艇的
I'm not getting in a lifeboat without my winnings,
而且我要把这家游轮公司告得死去活来
and I'm suing the hell out of this cruise line.
我们该怎么办
What do we do?
我们得找人帮我们把他弄上救生艇
Well, we're gonna need some help getting him to a lifeboat,
如果走到那一步的话
if it comes to that.
现在 我们先等等弃船的命令
For now, we wait on the order to abandon ship.
萝拉 留下来陪你丈夫
Lola, stay here with your husband.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
去找我妻子
To find my wife.
这感觉不像是回上面去的路
This doesn't feel like the way back up.
船在向左舷倾斜
The ship's listing portside.
我们得从船员厨房才能上去
We need to get to the crew galley to get back up.
这扎带真的有必要吗
Were these zip ties really necessary?
有必要
They're necessary.
我是个白领罪犯
I'm a white- collar criminal.
我又不是暴力罪犯
No danger to anyone.
这话跟诺曼·彼得森说去吧
Tell that to Norman Peterson.
你听到了吗
Do you hear that?
什么
- What?
喂 有人在下面吗
Hello? Is anybody down here?
帮我把他翻过来
Help me turn him over.
是斯科特·威斯汀 我们的首席通讯工程师
That's Scott Westin, our chief communications engineer.
你那白领现在被染上鲜血了
You just got a little more red on that white collar.
你知道是谁干的
You know who did this.
因为是你引他们来的
Because you brought them here.
天啊 蕾娜
Oh, God. Reyna!
你得帮我把她弄出来
You got to help me get her free.
不要试探我
Don't test mel
船长 你能站起来吗
Captain, can you stand?
我们得把你弄出去
We've got to get you out of here.
来
Come on!
我的胳膊断了 肋骨也断了
My arm's broken, some ribs.
我们得小心行事
We got to do this very carefully.
看 我的对讲机
Look, my radio.
她的对讲机
Her radio.
我是奥乔亚船长 收到了吗
This is Captain Ochoa. Do you copy?
船长 谢天谢地
Captain. Thank God.
听我说 海盗把船弄坏了
Listen to me. The pirates have hobbled the boat.
通讯服务器组上绑了个炸弹
There was a bomb rigged to the comm server.
左舷稳定器炸没了
The port stabilizers are gone.
船在进水
The ship is taking on water.
我们这边感觉到了
We felt it up here.
已经通知全体集合了
Uh, a- a general muster's been called.
好 是时候弃船了
Good. It's time to abandon ship.
让所有乘客和船员上救生艇
AlI passengers and crew into the lifeboats.
是啊 但是风暴
Yeah, but the storm- -
嗯 再等就来不及了
No, it'll only get worse.
我要去启动辅助舱底排水泵
I'm gonna activate the secondary bilge pump.
这应该能让我们在沉船前有足够的时间来
That should keep us afloat long enough
让所有救生艇下水
to launch all the lifeboats.
船长
－ Captain!
有点断断续续 船长
...breaking up. Captain
你们两个 到甲板上去
You two. Get above decks.
到指定的集合点报到
Report to your designated muster stations.
船长 你现在情况不好 做不了别的了
Captain, you're in no shape to do anything
让我们带你离开
but let us get you out of here.
总得有人去启动舱底排水泵
Somebody has to activate that bilge pump.
如果船侧倾 救生艇就下不了水了
The lifeboats can't launch if the ship is on its side.
好吧 我来 我来
AlI right, I'll do it, I'll do it.
什么
What?
我来 你告诉我该怎么做 我会照做
I'll do it. You tell me what to do, I'll do it.
穿过走廊 往下两层
Through that corridor, down two levels.
你会看到一个标志 这把钥匙可以打开面板
You'll see a sign. This key will open the panel.
把操纵杆移到泵的位置
Move the lever to the pump position
然后赶紧走
and then get the hell out of there.
明白
I got it.
你现在给我赎罪
You're gonna redeem your sorry ass.
把船长带到甲板上去
Get your captain above decks.
这一切都不是我的本意
I didn't mean for any of this to happen.
我不是个坏人
I'm not a bad person.
那就证明给我看
Then prove it!
我只是觉得 如果我是其他队长
I just feel like, if I was any other captain,
我就不会坐冷板凳了
I would not have been benched.
他可不会让鲍比暂停工作
He wouldn't have put Bobby in a timeout.
更别提那三个叛徒了
And don't even get me started on the three Judases.
好了 你现在激动起来了
Okay, now you're spiraling.
他们没有背叛你 他们只是想
They did not betray you, they were just
让你在这种情况下感觉好一点
trying to make you feel better about the situation.
完全正确 他们想安慰我
Exactly. They were trying to comfort me
因为他们默认是我搞砸了
because they assumed I screwed up.
也许是吧
Maybe I did.
我看了那小子一眼
I took one look at that kid
心想“有权有势的富二代混球”
and thought"entitled, rich brat. "
他确实是
He was.
这并不意味着他该死
It doesn't mean he deserved to die.
不是你杀的他
You didn't kill him.
我也没能救他
I didn't save him either.
他脑出血了 你救不了的
He had a brain bleed. You weren't going to.
宝贝
- - Baby.
你得试着放下这件事
You have to try to let this go.
你知道谁不会劝我放下吗
You know who's not gonna tell me to let it go?
不要在那个女人度假的时候打扰她
Do not bother that woman while she's on vacation.
你好 我是雅典娜·格
Hi, you've reached Athena G...
太烦人了
That is so annoying.
鲍比的电话也直接转到语音信箱了
Bobby's phone is going straight to voicemail, too.
他们在游轮上嘛
Well, they're on a cruise.
手机信号可能不太稳定
Cell service is probably spotty.
我昨天还和她视频了
I was FaceTiming with her yesterday.
嗯 那是飓风之前的事儿了
Well, that was before the hurricane.
什么什么
The what?
巴哈海岸有一场热带风暴来着
Yeah, there was a tropical storm off the coast of Baja.
刚刚还升级了
Just got upgraded.
什么 你为什么不早说
What? Why didn't you say something?
刚刚升级的
Well, it just got upgraded.
预计它不会在这里登陆
And it's not expected to make landfall here,
会返回大海
it's going back out to sea.
-返回大海  -对
- "Out to sea"? - Yeah.
你的意思是鲍比和雅典娜现在飘着的那个海马
You mean where Bobby and Athena currently are?
而且他们的电话一直转到语音信箱
Where their phones keep going straight to voicemail?
亨 他们是在游轮上 不是在米诺号上
Hen, they're on a cruise ship, not the S. S. Minnow.
这些船配备了
Those vessels are equipped for this,
很多技术和先进的导航系统
with lots of tech and advanced navigation.
它们能战胜任何天气
They can outmaneuver any weather system.
他们会没事的
They're gonna be fine.
-雅典娜  -大家都有
Athena! - There's room
-位置  -雅典娜
- for everyone. - Athena!
保持冷静
Just stay calm.
请有序前进 谢谢
Just proceed in an orderly fashion, thank you.
-嘿 韦斯  -纳什队长
Hey! Wesl Captain Nash.
我让事务长通知你
I sent the purser to let you know
等我们把大部分人送上救生艇
we'll transport Mr. Peterson as soon as we get
我们再把彼得森先生送上去
most of these people on lifeboats.
好 太好了 你看到我妻子了吗
Okay, that's great. Have you seen my wife?
-格兰特警佐吗  -对
- Sergeant Grant? - Yeah.
她不会还在赌场吧
She's not still in the casino?
没有 她去找你们的邮轮总监了
No, she went after your cruise director.
他逃走了
He slipped away.
我不知道他觉得他能逃去哪里
I don't know where he thought he could go.
她的乘客身份牌
Her passenger ID medallion- -
我们能用它找到她吗
can we use that to find her?
找不到 我收不到她的信号
Nothing. I'm not getting a signal from her.
也许她的身份牌坏了
Maybe her medallion was damaged.
爆炸是在哪里
The explosion, where did that happen?
-左舷的工程部  -左舷的工程部
Engineering, portside. Engineering, portside.
纳什队长
Captain Nash.
我不能让你下去
I can't allow you to go down there.
我没问你让不让
I'm not asking permission!
-纳什队长  -什么
Captain Nash. - Yeah?
-纳什队长  -嗯
Captain Nash...- Yeah.
如果不是你妻子
...if it wasn't for your wife,
我不可能从那里逃出来
I never would have made it out of there.
她在哪儿
Where is she?
去救我们了
Saving the ship.
她当然会去
Of course she is.
嘿 亨
Hey, Hen.
很抱歉打扰你工作了
I'm so sorry to bother you at work.
不 没问题 你现在不是该去值班了吗
No, it's no problem. Shouldn't you be on your shift?
你还没跟奇米说过话吗
You haven't spoken to Chimney?
说什么
About what?
好吧 他都告诉我了 真糟糕
Okay, he told me everything, and it sucks.
是啊
Yeah.
但我来不是为了这个
But that's not why I'm here.
这边走
Through here. - Um...
我是希望你能帮我个忙
I was hoping you could do me a favor.
行啊 你说
Yeah, name it.
你能联系海岸警卫队吗
Can you call the Coast Guard?
你船没了吗
Did you lose a boat?
还真是
Yes, actually.
鲍比和雅典娜的那艘游轮 乌诺号 我找不到它了
Bobby and Athena's cruise ship, the Uno, I can't find it.
你来看
Here, look.
这是太平洋上的所有船只
That is every boat on the Pacific right now.
他们的船不在上面
And theirs isn't on it.
我也给鲍比和雅典娜打了很多次电话了
I- I've tried to call Bobby and Athena numerous times.
都直接进了语音信箱
It's just going straight to voicemail.
好吧 但他们在海上 我觉得
Okay, but they're at sea, and I think
应该是发生了热带风暴
there's a tropical storm down there.
是飓风 它升级了
Hurricane. It's been upgraded.
我得找到他们
I need to find them.
好 行 我去打个电话问问
Yeah, okay, I- I will make a call.
好吗
Okay?
我听说你试图一个人拯救这艘船
Heard you were trying to save the ship by yourself.
你想要我们可以一起参与的活动
You wanted an activity we could do together.
现在这不就有了吗
I guess this is it.
好了 准备好了吗 开始
AlI right, ready? Let's go.
等等 手动控制在上面
Wait. Manual override is up here.
好了 看看我们能做点什么
AlI right, now. Let's see what we can do
防止这艘船
about keeping this tube of doom
彻底翻掉
from completely rolling on its side.
鲍比 门
Bobby, the door!
该死的
Damn it.
我们上次聊的时候 你表示过一此
So, the last time we spoke, you had expressed some trepidation
对于你们这次游轮蜜月之旅的惶恐 对吧
about this honeymoon cruise you're about to go on?
迟来的蜜月
Belated honeymoon.
而且我感觉惶恐这个词不太合适
And I'm not sure"trepidation" is the right word.
我只是觉得如果我们一结婚
I just think if our honeymoon had come
就去度蜜月 而不是四年之后再去
at the start of our marriage rather than four years into it,
感觉就不会这么
it wouldn't feel so.
严重
consequential.
此话怎讲
How so?
我向雅典娜求婚的时候
Well, when I asked Athena to marry me,
她处于一种非常脆弱的状态
she was in a very vulnerable place.
我们都是
We both were.
当时我刚在失去了一个重要的人之后
I- I had recently moved here from Minnesota
从明尼苏达搬到这里
after a loss.
而她又刚结束了一段20年的婚姻
And her marriage of 20 years had just imploded.
我求婚的时候我们才约会了几个月而已
We were only seeing each other a few months when I proposed.
有时候 从事你们这些职业的人
Sometimes when people do the kinds of jobs you do,
更能理解珍惜当下 不要过多等待的意义
they understand the urgency of now, of not waiting.
我求婚的时候基本就是这么说的
That's pretty much what I said when I proposed.
也没给她拒绝的机会
Didn't really give her a chance to say no.
你怕这次游轮之旅
And you're afraid going on this cruise
可能会给她这个机会
might give her that chance.
可能惶恐确实是对的形容
Maybe"trepidation"is the right word.
想听听我的建议吗
My advice?
去吧
Go.
享受一些和你太太独处的时光
Enjoy some time alone with your wife.
好了
AlI right.
行吧
Okay.
-你没事吧  -没事
Are you okay? - Yeah.
-没事  -没事吧
- Yeah. - You're okay?
行 这没用
AlI right, that's not gonna work.
好 行
AlI right. Okay.
我们在里面
We're in here!
鲍比
Bobby!
没人能听见的
Nobody's gonna hear.
这不一定的
We don't know that yet.
宝贝
Baby.
所有人都在上救生艇
Everybody's getting into the lifeboats.
我们做了
We did
必须要做的事
what we had to do.
雅典娜
Athena.
我真的很抱歉
I am so sorry.
你没必要道歉
You have nothing to be sorry for.
不 我有 如果不是我 你都不会在这里
No, I do. You wouldn't even be here if it weren't for me.
你都不想来着狗屁游轮旅行 是我逼你的
You didn't want to come on this damn cruise. I made you.
我他妈到底在想什么
What the hell was I thinking
-我怎么配得上这样第二次机会  -不不不 鲍比
to deserve a second chance like this? - No, no, no, Bobby.
-别说了 别说了  -不
Stop. Stop. - No.
我配不上你 雅典娜 我从来都配不上你
I don't deserve you, Athena. I never did.
但你答应了我
But you said yes.
-再来一次我也还是会答应你的  -我无权向你求婚
- And I would again. - I didn't have a right to ask you.
在我所做的一切之后 我没能救下我的第一个家庭
Not after what I did. I couldn't save my first family.
我也救不了你
I can't save you either.
你已经救了我了
You already did that, baby.
获得第二次机会的不是只有你
You're not the only one getting a second chance here.
你也没有逼我做任何事
And you didn't make me do anything.
我在这里是因为我想
I'm here because I want to be.
-和你一起  -雅典娜
With you. - Athena...
是的 我是很害怕
And, yes, I was afraid.
我是害怕 自己不知道要如何
I was afraid that I, I wouldn't know how to be
和你在一起
with you
如果没有了那些杂音的话
without all the noise.
我怕在我们真正独处的时候
And when we were really, truly alone,
我会不知道该说什么
I- I- I would have nothing to say,
但现在我发现我有很多
but now I find that I have lots,
有很多想说的
lots to say
但是没有时间了
but not enough time.
我爱你 老公
I love you, husband.
我爱你 我爱你 老婆
I love you. I love you, my wife.
我爱你
I love you.
雅典娜 你抓住
Athena, grab hold.
抓住那根管子
Grab hold of that pipe.
去吧
Go ahead.
你抓住 抓住
You hold on, hold on.
好
Okay.
不
Oh, no!
鲍比 鲍比
Bobby! Bobby!
你坚持住 你坚持住
You hang on, you hang on.
坚持住 坚持住
Hang on, hang on.
你们俩怎么这么久
What the hell's taking you two so long?
上面的人都快疯了 走啊
People are losing their minds up there, come on.
局长
Chief.
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
我的办公室就在这楼里
My office is in the building.
我本来要给你打电话的 然后他们告诉我
I was actually about to call you, then I was told
你在这里的前台刷了身份卡进来了
you'd swiped your ID badge at the front desk.
我只是来找朋友的
I'm just here visiting a friend.
挺好
That's good.
我还是想当面告诉你
Better you hear this in person.
你可以复工了
You can go back to work.
什么
What?
毒理检验结果出来了
The tox results are in.
凯尔·奥尔蒂斯体内的酒精含量超出了法定标准的两倍
Kyle Ortiz was more than double the legal limit.
而且他们在他体内发现了甲基芾丙胺（冰毒）
And they found traces of methamphetamine in his system.
显然那小伙子一直在挣扎
Clearly the young man had been struggling.
很遗憾
I'm sorry to hear that.
至于洛杉矶消防局这里
As far as the LAFD is concerned,
我们认为你的行为是专业且妥当的
you acted professionally and appropriately.
谢谢你 局长
Thanks, Chief.
我已经通知了科利尔队长
I've already informed Captain Collier
他会把118署交还给你
that he'll be handing the 118 back over to you.
其实
Um, actually
他可以不用还给我的
what if, what if he didn't?
你说什么
I beg your pardon?
长官
Sir...
我来这里
the reason I'm here- -
是为了找纳什队长和他太太
I'm looking for Captain Nash and his wife.
我找不到他们那艘游轮了
I can't find their cruise ship.
什么叫你找不到他们那艘游轮了
You can't find their cruise ship?
你看
Look here.
他们最后出现的地点就在这里
Their last known location was right here.
在墨西哥海岸边
Just off the coast of Mexico.
自那之后 海上的一场热带风暴
Since then, a tropical storm down there
已经发展为五级飓风了
has developed into a Cat 5 lhurricane.
船只有发出求救信号吗
Was there an SOS from the ship?
没有 但我觉得我们应该考虑
No, but I think that we should consider
投入资源去帮忙寻找他们
deploying resources to help look for them.
-但我们不是海岸警卫队  -海岸警卫队
- But we're not the Coast Guard. - The Coast Guard
现在在处理飓风相关事务 忙不过来
has its hands full with the hurricane.
而且也没有人实际求救啊
And no one's actually called for help.
可能是因为他们无法求救 长官
Maybe because they can't, sir.
威尔逊队长 洛杉矶消防局
Captain Wilson, the LAFD has no jurisdiction
无权管辖墨西哥海岸外的海域
over the waters off the coast of Mexico.
而且如果他们在风暴变为飓风之前
And if they reversed course before that storm achieved
就改变了路径 那应该是没事的
hurricane status, they should be well out of harm's way.
我的直觉说不是这样的
My gut tells me otherwise.
你的直觉
Your gut?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
威尔逊队长
Captain Wilson,
我们的任务是保护洛杉矶的人们
our job is to protect the people of Los Angeles.
请你回到118消防局
You will report back for duty
作为队长复职
at the 118 firehouse as its captain.
我会通知科利尔队长 说你要过去了
I'II let Captain Collier know you're on your way
所以
So.
这看着好像不太妙
that didn't look super fun.
确实不太行
Could have gone better.
你被炒了吗
Are you fired?
还没有
Not yet.
但可能会吧
But I probably will be.
墨西哥的紧急求救电话是多少
What's the number for the 911 in Mexico?
所以救生艇都出去了吗
So the lifeboats got launched?
大部分 是的
Most of them did, yes.
多少人下去了
How many people got off?
基本所有人都下去了 多亏了你们俩
Well, practically everyone, thanks to you two.
你们让船保持了足够长时间的直立 来疏散乘客
You kept her upright long enough for the evacuation.
但现在船撑不住了
But that's it.
所以还剩下谁
So who's left?
就剩我们几个了
Just a handful of us, really.
我觉得你是对的
Well, I think you're right.
确实出事了
Something's happened.
今早大概10点左右
At around 10: 00 a. m. this morning,
有二十几个求救电话
more than two dozen 911 calls came
打到了墨西哥中部沿海紧急呼叫中心
into coastal emergency call centers in Central Mexico.
所有电话都挂断了
AlI of them dropped.
也就差不多正好是
Which is just about the time
乌诺号从雷达上消失的时候
that the Uno disappeared from radar.
这不可能是巧合
That can't be a coincidence.
应该不是
Probably not. FD
帮我个忙 别接电话
Oh! Do me a favor, don't answer that.
等我离开这栋楼再接
At least not until I'm out of the building.
我现在真的不想再被质疑了
I really don't feel like being second- guessed right now.
他们回来了 诺曼 纳什队长和格兰特警佐
They're back, Norman, Captain Nash and Sergeant Grant.
怎么没人把他送走啊
No one got him out of here?
你们不回来 他不肯走
He wouldn't leave without you.
-很高兴见到你们俩  -我们也是
- It's good to see you both. - Good to be seen.
-就这些人了吗  -我的大副肯尼斯在桥楼上
This is all of us? - My first mate Kenneth is on the bridge.
-他在试图发出求救信号  -通讯恢复了吗
He's trying to send a distress call. - The comms are back up?
没有
Not exactly.
有大浪来了
Wave coming!
所有人抓稳了
Everybody brace yourselves!
-我的天  -鲍比
· Oh, my Godl Bobby!
我的天
Oh, my God.